<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <section id="WebApplicationDescriptorParameters"  xreflabel="WebApplicationDescriptorParameters">
  <?dbhtml filename="WebApplicationDescriptorParameters.html" ?>

  <chapterinfo>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>Descriptor</keyword>

      <keyword>JSF</keyword>

      <keyword>Ajax4jsf</keyword>
    </keywordset>
  </chapterinfo>

      <title>Web Application Descriptor parameters</title>
      <para>These parameters help with development and increase the flexibility of Ajax4jsf use.</para>
          <para>
          <table>
              <title>Initialization Parameters</title>
              <tgroup cols="3">
                  <thead>
                      <row>
                          <entry>Name</entry>
                          <entry>Default</entry>
                          <entry>Description</entry>
                      </row>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody>
                      <row>
                          <entry>org.ajax4jsf.LOGFILE</entry>
                          <entry>none</entry>
                          <entry>
                       The is an URL to an application or a container log file (if possible). If this parameter is set, a content from the given URL will be shown on a <emphasis ><property>Debug</property></emphasis> error page in the <emphasis ><property>iframe</property></emphasis> window 
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                      <row>
                          <entry>org.ajax4jsf.VIEW_HANDLERS</entry>
                          <entry>none</entry>
                          <entry>
                              Is a comma-separated list of custom <emphasis ><property>"ViewHandler"</property></emphasis> instances 
                              for inserting in chain. Handlers are inserted in the given order. So must be used if the order of them is important. 
                              No need to define ajax4jsf handler there, as it will be always the first.  
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                      <row>
                          <entry> org.ajax4jsf.CONTROL_COMPONENTS</entry>
                          <entry>none</entry>
                          <entry>
                             Is a comma-separated list of names for a component as a special control case, such as messages bundle loader, alias bean components, etc. Is a type of component got by a reflection from the static field <emphasis ><property>COMPONENT_TYPE</property></emphasis>. For components with such types encode methods always are called in rendering AJAX responses, even if a component isn&apos;t in an updated part 
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                      <row>
                          <entry>org.ajax4jsf.ENCRYPT_RESOURCE_DATA</entry>
                          <entry>false</entry>
                          <entry>
                              For generated resources, such as encrypt generation data, it&apos;s encoded in the resource URL. For example, URL for an image generated from the <emphasis ><property>mediaOutput</property></emphasis> component contains a name of a generation method, since for a hacker attack, it is possible to create a request for any JSF baked beans or other attributes. To prevent such attacks, set this parameter to true in critical applications (works with JRE > 1.4)
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                      <row>
                          <entry>org.ajax4jsf.ENCRYPT_PASSWORD</entry>
                          <entry>random</entry>
                          <entry>
                              Is a password for encrypt resources data. If isn&apos;t set, random password is used 
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                      <row>
                          <entry>org.ajax4jsf.SKIN</entry>
                          <entry>DEFAULT</entry>
                          <entry>Is a name of a skin used in an application. It can be a literal string with a skin name, or the <emphasis ><property>EL</property></emphasis> expression (#{...}) pointed to a <emphasis ><property>String</property></emphasis> property (skin name) or a property with the type org.ajax4jsf.framework.skin. Skin in last case, this instance will be used as a current skin
                          </entry>
                      </row>
					  <row>
                          <entry>org.ajax4jsf.COMPRESS_SCRIPT</entry>
                          <entry>true</entry>
                          <entry>It doesn&apos;t allow A4J to reformat JavaScript files (makes it impossible to debug)
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                  </tbody>
              </tgroup>
          </table>
          </para>
          <para>
          <table>
              <title>org.ajax4jsf.Filter Initialization Parameters</title>
              <tgroup cols="3">
                  <thead>
                      <row>
                          <entry>Name</entry>
                          <entry>Default</entry>
                          <entry>Description</entry>
                      </row>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody>
                      <row>
                          <entry>log4j-init-file</entry>
                          <entry>-</entry>
                          <entry>Is a path (relative to web application context) to the log4j.xml configuration file, it can be used to setup per-application custom logging
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                      <row>
                          <entry>enable-cache</entry>
                          <entry>true</entry>
                          <entry>Enables caching of framework-generated resources (Javascript, CSS, images, etc). For debug purposes - development custom JavaScript or Style - prevent to use old cached in browser
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                      <row>
                          <entry>forceparser</entry>
                          <entry>true</entry>
                          <entry>
                              Forces parsing by a filter <emphasis ><property>HTML</property></emphasis> syntax checker on any JSF page. If false, only AJAX responses are parsed to syntax check and conversion to well-formed XML. Setting to false improve performance, but can provide visual effects on AJAX updates
                          </entry>
                      </row>
                  </tbody>
              </tgroup>
          </table>
          </para>
  </section>