<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="introduction" xreflabel="introduction">
    <?dbhtml filename="introduction.html"?>

    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
          The Photo Album Demo
          is created to help you imagine the way web applications designed and developed with <property>RichFaces</property> can look like and behave.
    </para>
    <para>
          The <property>RichFaces</property> is an opensource framework and library of Ajax-capable UI components for JavaServer Faces framework. 
          The <property>RichFaces</property> is evolved from Ajax4JSF framework (integration of Ajax and JavaServer Faces technologies). 
    </para>
      <para>
            The <property>RichFaces</property> provides a set of benefits which distinguish it from a wide range of similar libraries and frameworks. 
            All the <property>RichFaces</property> benefits and advantages are fully described in the 
            &quot;<ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/file-access/default/members/jbossrichfaces/freezone/docs/devguide/en/html/Introduction.html">Introduction to the RichFaces</ulink>&quot; chapter of the 
            &quot;<ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/file-access/default/members/jbossrichfaces/freezone/docs/devguide/en/html/index.html">RichFaces Developer  Guide</ulink>&quot;.
            The &quot;<emphasis role="bold">Photo Album Demo</emphasis>&quot; covers some of the main ones and demonstrates: 
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para><emphasis>Wide variety of UI components</emphasis> — the <property>RichFaces</property> provides a Lego-like way of building user interfaces for web applications;</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis>Built-in Ajax capability</emphasis> — the <property>RichFaces</property> offers both component-wide and very flexible page-wide Ajax support with no need to write any JavaScript code; </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis>Highly customizable look-and-feel</emphasis> — the <property>RichFaces</property> have special feature called 
                  &quot;<ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/file-access/default/members/jbossrichfaces/freezone/docs/devguide/en/html/ArchitectureOverview.html#Skinnability">Skinnability</ulink>&quot;).</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
            The &quot;Photo Album Demo&quot; is a desktop-like on-line photo manager. 
            It provides social services for  uploading photos, storing and previewing them, creating your own albums and sharing them with other users, searching albums, photos or users, managing the environment. 
            Newcomers or not registered users can navigate through other users shelves and albums in &quot;Anonymous mode&quot;, but in this case <property>no</property> possibilities to create personal shelves or albums or upload photos are available.
      </para>
      <para>
            The &quot;Photo Album Demo&quot;  represents and implements strict  &quot;Shelves—Albums—Photos&quot; hierarchy. 
            It means that photos are kept in albums and albums are stored on shelves, but albums can not contain another albums or shelves and shelves can not keep another shelves and can not be stored in albums.
      </para>
      <para>
            The <property>RichFaces</property> &quot;Photo Album Demo&quot; is a blue print application. One of it main goal is to show patterns of  the <property>RichFaces</property> components usage.  
      </para>          
</chapter>

     
