<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<chapter id="chap-Component_Reference-Common_features">
	<title>Common features</title>
	<para>
		This chapter covers those attributes and features that are common to many of the components in the tag libraries.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Common_features-Positioning_in_popup_components">
		<title>Positioning and appearance of components</title>
		<para>
			A number of attributes relating to positioning and appearance are common to several components.
		</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><varname>disabled</varname></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Specifies whether the component is disabled, which disallows user interaction.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><varname>focus</varname></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						References the <varname>id</varname> of an element on which to focus after a request is completed on the client side.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><varname>height</varname></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The height of the component in pixels.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><varname>dir</varname></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Specifies the direction in which to display text that does not inherit its writing direction. Valid values are <literal>LTR</literal> (left-to-right) and <literal>RTL</literal> (right-to-left).
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><varname>style</varname></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Specifies Cascading Style Sheet (<acronym>CSS</acronym>) styles to apply to the component.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><varname>styleClass</varname></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Specifies one or more <acronym>CSS</acronym> class names to apply to the component.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><varname>width</varname></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The width of the component in pixels.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Common_features-Calling_available_JavaScript_methods">
		<title>Calling available JavaScript methods</title>
		<para>
			Client-side JavaScript methods can be called using component events. These JavaScript methods are defined using the relevant event attribute for the component tag. Methods are referenced through typical Java syntax within the event attribute, while any parameters for the methods are obtained through the <varname>data</varname> attribute, and referenced using <acronym>JSF</acronym> Expression Language (<acronym>EL</acronym>). <xref linkend="exam-Component_Reference-data-Data_reference_example" /> a simple reference to a JavaScript method with a single parameter.
		</para>
		<para>
			Refer to <xref linkend="sect-Component_Reference-Common_Ajax_attributes-Events_and_JavaScript_interactions" /> or to event descriptions unique to each component for specific usage.
		</para>
	</section>

</chapter>

