<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

<chapter id="chap-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs">
	<title>Rich inputs</title>
	<para>
		This chapter details rich components for user input and interaction.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richCalendar">
		<title>&lt;rich:Calendar&gt;</title>
		<para>
			The <classname>&lt;rich:calendar&gt;</classname> component allows the user to enter a date and time through an in-line or pop-up calendar. The pop-up calendar can navigate through months and years, and its look and feel can be highly customized.
		</para>
		<para>
			The <classname>&lt;rich:calendar&gt;</classname> component supports two different ways of loading data through defining the <code>mode</code> attribute. When not specified, the component uses <literal>client</literal> mode, which loads an initial portion of data within a set date range. The range can be defined by using the <code>preloadDateRangeBegin</code> and <code>preloadDateRangeEnd</code> attributes. Additional data requests are not sent. Alternatively, with <code>mode="ajax"</code> the <classname>&lt;rich:calendar&gt;</classname> requests portions of data for rendering from a special data model. The data model can be defined through the <code>dataModel</code> attribute, which points to an object that implements the <classname>CalendarDataModel</classname> interface. If the <code>dataModel</code> attribute is not defined or has a value of <literal>null</literal>, the <literal>ajax</literal> mode functions the same as the <literal>client</literal> mode.
		</para>
		<para>
			The <classname>&lt;rich:calendar&gt;</classname> component is presented as a pop-up by default, appearing as a text input with a button to expand the full pop-up calendar. Specifying <code>popup="false</code> will render the calendar in-line on the page instead, which displays the full calendar without the text input or display button. The appearance of the display button can be altered from the standard calendar icon by defining the <code>buttonIcon</code> and <code>buttonIconDisabled</code> attributes to replace the icon with a specified file, or by defining the <code>buttonLabel</code> attribute to display text on the button without an icon. If <code>buttonLabel</code> is specified then both <code>buttonIcon</code> and <code>buttonIconDisabled</code> attributes are ignored.
		</para>
		<para>
			
		</para>
		
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richcolorPicker">
		<title>&lt;rich:colorPicker&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richcomboBox">
		<title>&lt;rich:comboBox&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richeditor">
		<title>&lt;rich:editor&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richfileUpload">
		<title>&lt;rich:fileUpload&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richinplaceInput">
		<title>&lt;rich:inplaceInput&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richinplaceSelect">
		<title>&lt;rich:inplaceSelect&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richinputNumberSlider">
		<title>&lt;rich:inputNumberSlider&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richinputNumberSpinner">
		<title>&lt;rich:inputNumberSpinner&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Component_Reference-Rich_inputs-richsuggestionBox">
		<title>&lt;rich:suggestionBox&gt;</title>
		<para>
			Incomplete
		</para>
	</section>

</chapter>

